Jade Vance

jade.nicole.vance@gmail.com // Github // LinkedIn // Twitter // 321-276-1465

Summary

Hi I'm Jade! In a previous life, I worked in science. I've spent the last year transitioning to software. Why? I love solving problems and the instant gratification it offers. My strengths include strong intuition and debugging. I am very good at connecting with people across teams. My weaknesses include dogs of all shapes and sizes.

Experience

MICROSOFT

Redmond, WA
October 2016 - Present

Intern: Windows Devices / Engineering Services

Assisted in design and implementation of a web-based tool to handle the internal management of physical machine checkout and reclamation. This included:

- Creating and implementing user stories
- Reviewing deliverables with a PM and planning sprints
- Researching technical solutions in open source libraries
- wrote C# server-side code to retrieve data from DocumentDB storage
- wrote Javascript code to handle display and manipulation of data

Refactored a legacy application for physical machine checkout and reclamation. This included:

- Reading and understanding the existing code
- Gathering documentation and requirements to understand the application
- Identifying and fixing bugs in Javascript
- Redesigning API endpoints to follow RESTful conventions

ADA DEVELOPERS ACADEMY

Seattle, WA Jan 2016 – Feb 2017

Software Development Student

Learned and worked in web technologies with focus on:

- Ruby / Ruby on Rails
- JavaScript / NodeJS
- APIs client and server-side
- ∘ Git
- Practiced Test Driven Development techniques for all projects
- Followed agile methodologies for all group projects
- Utilized Trello to organize project workflow

Featured Projects

Fuzz Therapy // GitHub Repo: Swift iOS // GitHub Repo: Rails API

• Built a social dog iOS app with OAuth login and SSL endpoint encryption. Leaveraged Swift and Rails libraries to implement caching and photo retrieval from Amazon S3 -> Rails API -> iOS device.

FarMar Rails // GitHub Repo

• Built a postgres database backed Rails application to view, create, and manage relational entities.

Fandom Formatter // GitHub Repo

• Built a Rails application with a text parser that can translate Google Docs to clean HTML. Explored how to use OAuth for logging in to Google.

US BIOTEK LABORATORIES

Seattle, WA 2011 – 2015

SENIOR CHEMIST

- Method Development: Built a proprietary scientific test from inception to validation.
- Works with in-house developers to design, test and execute new software modules in Laboratory Management Systems, including:
 - Gathering requirements for automated worklist generation
 - Designing a way to sort doctors' orders for faster specimen turnaround-times

BLOOD SYSTEMS LABORATORIES/CREATIVE TESTING SOLUTIONS

Tempe, AZ 2004 – 2010

CLINICAL LABORATORY SPECIALIST IV

- Worked as shift supervisor
- Performed time-critical testing on organ donations

Education

ARIZONA STATE UNIVERSITY

Tempe, AZ 2003 – 2005

Bachelor of Science: Biology

• Minor: Chemistry

• Graduated with cum laude honors